## Graham Alexander Noblit, Ph.D.

(647) 855-7894 · GrahamNoblit@pm.me

linkedin.com/in/graham-noblit · www.GrahamNoblit.com · github.com/gnoblit

**Summary**: Adaptable data scientist (4+ years exp. in R & Python) with expertise in interpretable models; a broad statistical toolkit; and analyzing big, messy, and observational data. Enjoys collaborating, presenting, and leadership-roles. **Objective**: Seeking data science position in with machine-learning and leadership growth opportunities.

#### **EDUCATION**

Harvard University, Ph.D. in Human Evolutionary Biology, Cambridge, MA University of Texas at Austin, B.A. in Anthropology, Minor in Mathematics, Austin, TX

May 2022

May 2012

### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

**Professional**: R · Python (Numpy, Scikit-learn, Pandas) · Julia · SQL · Git · Econometrics & Causal Inference · Machine Learning · Data Visualization · Geospatial Data · Reinforcement Learning · Game Theory · Survey Design · LaTeX

### RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Univ. of Toronto: Schwartz Reisman Inst. & Vector Inst. for Artificial Intelligence Post-Doctoral Scientist

Toronto, ON 2022-Present

- Construct mathematical model of norm-behavior using computational (Python, Julia) and analytical (game-theoretic) methods, with applications to artificial intelligence and reinforcement learning
- Design collaborative project and devise survey questions studying legal order (Kenya)
- Mentor a Ph.D. student's research and direct and lead weekly Schwartz Reisman Graduate Fellows' meetings
  planning a research workshop advancing interdisciplinary artificial intelligence and machine learning research
- Plan and develop themes and speakers for interdisciplinary conference (100+ attendees) on artificial intelligence

### Research Consultant (Self-Employed), Remote

2019-Present

• Provide statistical and disciplinary expertise and services for academic researchers and projects at Harvard University and The University of Chicago: Booth School of Business and industry projects at Rare (behavioral change fisheries project in Brazilian Amazon) and DeepMind (development of novel multi-agent reinforcement learning algorithm permitting artificial intelligence system to learn norms and emergent cooperative behaviors)

### RESEARCH & TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# Harvard University Doctoral Researcher (Computational Social Science/Cultural Evolution)

Cambridge, MA 2016-2022

- Produced 3 scientific articles identifying and answering questions on human societal, psychological, and institutional evolution, requiring statistical (R), analytical (game-theoretic), and computational (Python, Julia) methods
- Applied spatial and non-spatial linear models (R) and causal inference techniques to large ( $\sim$ 5-10 million observations) and small ( $\sim$ 5-10k) datasets for dissertation research
- Cleaned, processed, and analyzed messy data of various types (survey, economic, ecological, historical) and scales (individual, household, administrative, and geospatial)
- Designed and maintained multiple project pipelines simultaneously: identifying research questions; gathering, cleaning, and processing data; coding and performing statistical analyses; authoring reports; and presenting results
- Presented research regularly to technical and non-technical audiences including academic labs, research groups, and the leading international conference in my discipline (audiences ranged from  $\sim 5$  to  $\sim 50$  people)

# Harvard University Lead Teaching Fellow, Statistics

Cambridge, MA 2019-2021

Managed and directed teaching teams ranging in size from 5-15 teaching assistants

### Teaching Fellow, Human Evolutionary Biology & General Education

2018-2021

- Taught complex concepts to large (~250 students) and small (~30) classes including Introduction to Statistics for Economics, Game Theory and Psychology, and Artificial Intelligence and Philosophy
- Led in-person and online instruction using platforms including Zoom and Canvas

## LEADERSHIP & CONSULTING

### Research Project Manager, Harvard University & University of Toronto

2020-Present

 Leading collaborations across Harvard University, the University of Chicago: Booth School of Business, Toronto University, and Berkeley University

### Referee, NeurIPS (Academic Society), IEEE SaTML, Remote

2021-Present

• Refereed articles for major artificial intelligence and machine learning safety conferences